#### **SUMMARY**

Aldo is an experienced full-stack web developer with over a decade of experience working remotely with a large variety of technologies. He is equally comfortable collaborating with a team of developers or flying solo. He has worked with satisfied clients from the US, Israel, Argentina, and Europe.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Fullstack Developer**

Leasup Landlord. 2023 – Today

- Authentication and Security Enhancements: Streamlined login processes, updated and managed credentials, ensuring robust security and user authentication.
- o Image Management and Uploads: Implemented and refined image upload features for both properties and units, enhancing the user interface and functionality.
- Property and Unit Management: Developed billing address creation for properties, improved property creation flows, and refined unit management features including addition/removal of fields, sorting, and display enhancements.
- UI/UX Development and Improvements: Applied Tailwind CSS for UI styling enhancements, improved form fields and layouts for a better user experience, and optimized navigation and layout for ease of use.
- Production Configurations and External Integrations: Configured production environment settings, integrated with Salesforce for syncing properties and units, contributing to seamless external data management.
- o General Fixes and Refactoring: Addressed various bugs and performed code refactoring for improved maintainability and performance.
- o Technologies: Ruby on Rails 7, Ruby 3.2, Salesforce, Tailwind CSS, security and authentication, image handling, CSS, HTML, property and unit management.

#### Fullstack Developer

Affinipay. 2022 – Today

Working on their email service, for enterprise and consumers email templates.
 Developed an interactive email template builder using React. This feature allows users to visually construct and customize email templates using a drag-and-drop interface.
 Integrated with Liquid templates, it provides real-time previews and adjustments, enabling both enterprise and consumer users to create templates directly from the

administration pages. This builder enhances user experience by simplifying complex coding requirements and offering a wide array of styling and layout options.

- Writing tests an improving code quality.
- o Technologies: Ruby on Rails 6, React, Liquid templates, erb, Rspec, git, Docker

#### **Fullstack Developer**

Daasity. 2021 - 2022

- Working as fullstack developer, both on their integrations and platform teams.
  Optimized webpacker performance on platform application.
- Created new screens for Amazon data migrations.
- Added new tests and specs. Setup Capybara.
- Conduct Ruby on Rails (Turbo and Stimulus) training for new team members.

Technologies: Ruby on Rails, Bootstrap 3, SQLite, Rspec, GIT.

#### **Fullstack Developer**

360Insights. 2020 - 2021

- Designed and built an application for Ignite, John Player Special. Ignite (UK and Ireland) is an online platform that allows tobacco retailers in the UK and Ireland to enter orders. It also manages promotions and their rewards service.
  - o Implemented updates on JPS models and serializers to support new requirements (new rewards settings, reworked their order confirmations).
  - Separated their actual CMS to handle legal and administrative changes required after Brexit on both markets, Ireland and UK, which included disabling rewards and promotions.

Technologies: Ruby on Rails 6, Active Model serializer, Swagger, React, Bootstrap 3, SQLite, Rspec, GIT.

#### Web Developer

Publicis Groupe (via TEAM International). 2017 - 2020

- Develop an application from the ground up; also configured the projects structure and application skeleton.
- Implemented audit for campaigns/line items changes.
- Code reviews and training new team members.
- Migrating from AngularJS to Angular and React.

- Created reusable React components for the date picker, dropdown and input styles according to the provided designs.
- Delivered application screens: new line item, forecasting, reset password flow, audit screen, and administration pages.

Technologies: Angular, AngularJS, Redux, TypeScript, REST Api, Jasmine, React, Ruby on Rails 6.0, Rspec, FactoryBot, Capybara, Devise

#### **Frontend Developer**

Conversant Media (via Admios). 2016 – 2017

- Created and improved graphical D3.js campaign/line items spend widgets, allowing to plot by type and dates.
- Implemented their application audit.
- Implemented i18n for campaigns allowing to switch currencies per campaign or client.
- Code reviews and training new team members.

Technologies: AngularJS, D3.js, REST Api, Jasmine.

#### **Fullstack Developer**

Spork Labs. 2015 -2016

www.tofw.com

• Implemented their new websites for events for girls and women at Deseret Book allowing fast modifications on pages by the client using Prismic.io.

www.ldsliving.com

• Improving and refactoring front page and admin sections.

www.deseretbook.com

• Implementing their new subscription feature and digital variants.

Technologies: Ruby on Rails, RoR API, AWS, Spree, MongoDB, AngularJS, Prismic.io, Slim templates and bootstrap.

#### **Frontend Developer**

Yekra. 2015 - 2015

• Implemented their new infrastructure using MongoDB and Firebase for authentication and persistance.

Technologies: Ruby on Rails, AWS, MongoDB, Firebase, AngularJS, Google material design.

#### **Team Lead and Developer**

ExactTarget (via Admios). 2012-2015.

Cotweet (actually Salesforce): Cotweet allowed businesses to manage multiple Twitter or Facebook accounts and track social media conversations. Team leader and fullstack developer.

- Maintenance and implementing their new authentication and security questions system that required all information persisted to be encrypted in order to apply a client's demands (encrypted questions and replies using Blowfish cypher).
- Migrated their database to Salesforce using Hadoop.
- Was in charge of several security audit.

Technologies: Ruby on Rails 3.1.1, Backbone.js, Angular.js, AWS, Ruby 1.9.2, jquery, SQLite, Rspec, Cucumber, GIT, Hadoop.

#### **Ruby Developer**

*Chartlogic.* 2011-2012

Stella. An EHR (Electronic Health Record) overlay, helping hospitals meet the new Stage 2 Meaningful Use (MU) requirements by enabling physicians to easily create standardized continuity of care documents on Apple iPad.

- Implemented their frontend with Backbone.js (on a very early stage by the time we started using it).
- Implemented voice recognition using Dragon SDK.

Technologies: Ruby on Rails 3.1.1, Datamapper, Backbone.js, Coffeescript, Ruby 1.9.2, jquery, SQLite, Rspec, GIT.

#### **Ruby Developer**

Matchbin, 2011-2011

Matchbin's Community Marketplace provides existing communities with the ability to enhance their current web presence. Matchbin is a social media system, web content management system and ecommerce marketplace.

- Linux server admin
- Rails 2 & 3 development
- Deployment with Capistrano
- Performance optimization w/ Rails metal, Membase and Sphinx

Technologies: Rails, MySQL, Ajax, Javascript, Linux, git.

#### **Ruby Developer**

Spork Labs. 2010-2011

Implemented several websites related to every mobile os available, based upon Matchbin's CMS and some new features such as widgets support.

Still working websites: www.precentral.net, www.androidcentral.com. Development and sysadmin.

Technologies: Ruby on Rails 2.3.5, Ruby 1.8.7(ree), jquery, MySql, GIT.

#### **Ruby Developer**

Rallyhood (via Koombea). 2010 – 2011

A web application that gives you consumer-friendly project management tools to facilitate all the "work" that happens outside the office -- team sports, helping a sick family member, school activities, non-profit causes.

Technologies: Ruby on Rails 2.3.5, Ruby 1.8.7(ree), jquery, MySql, Rspec, Cucumber, Capybara, GIT.

#### **Ruby Developer**

Fleet Ventures. 2009 - 2010

**Vibrant**: Hospital management system. Ruby developer

Technologies: Ruby on Rails 3.0 (final), Ruby 1.8.7(ree), datamapper, devise, Jquery, Jquery UI, haml and sass, Sqlite3, Rspec, GIT.

Stella: EHR (Electronic Health Record) Ruby developer

Technologies: Ruby on Rails 2.3.5, Ruby 1.8.7, Jquery, Jquery UI, HAML, Compass, MySql, Photoshop, GIT, Rspec, Cucumber.

**Maytag Benchmark**: Home Appliance Center Web scraping and Cobol data recovery. Team leader and developer.

Technologies: Ruby on Rails 2.3.2, HAML, Compass, MySql, Photoshop, SVN.

#### **Web Developer**

Belatrix. (2008 – 2009)

**Blackwell – Velocity**: is a British academic book retailer and library supply service. Team size: 6 engineers. Developer

Technologies: C#, SQL Server, DB/2, Oracle (PL/SQL). Microsoft Visual Studio Team Suite 2008, Sharepoint.

Internal Human Resources Application Team size: 2 engineers. Team Lead. Developer

Technologies: C#, SQL Server.

**Matchbin** – **Aculis**: Matchbin's Community Marketplace provides existing communities with the ability to enhance their current web presence. Matchbin is a social media system, web content management system and ecommerce marketplace.

Team size: Several teams distributed by regions, 4 engineers locally. Developer

Technologies: Rails 1.2.3, MySQL, Ajax, Javascript, Linux, SVN.

#### **FREELANCE**

#### 2001 – 2008 Freelance Developer

Sterilization company of surgical tools (2007 – 2008) Development of a Web and data entry system.

Technology: Ruby on Rails, MySql, SVN.

System manager, data entry, invoice and supplier control.

#### **FACULTAD SAN FRANCISCO**

#### 2002 - 2003 Technical Support

Maintenance and repair of computers. Software installation.

### **Professional Development**

#### **Deep Learning: Neural Networks from Scratch**

Institution: UTN (Universidad Tecnológica Nacional), Buenos Aires

Issued: November 2023

Credential ID: CER-UYEK746T-1156531

#### **Machine Learning with Python**

Institution: UTN (Universidad Tecnológica Nacional), Buenos Aires

Issued: October 2023

Credential ID: CER-DKVO0SX2-1092814

#### **Education**

#### **FACULTAD SAN FRANCISCO - UCA**

**Bachelor in Information Systems** 

#### Languages

#### **English**

**Upper Intermediate** 

#### Chinese

Basic

### Skills

Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Javascript, Typescript, Angular, React, BDD, Jquery, NodeJS, C#